Andrew Nicholson

m: (540) 728-0119 | e: andrew.nicholson4491@gmail.com

I am a software engineer with 7+ years professional experience building enterprise software with a focus on best practices who understands how to manage the complexities of delivering high-quality, mission-critical software in a fast-paced business environment.

Work Experience

Full-Stack React/C# Developer; Pluralsight, LLC; Salt Lake City, UT November 2018 – present

- Joined as part of 2019 acquisition of GitPrime, Inc.
- Engineer software using JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, C#, and PostgreSQL

Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Developer; SciMed Solutions, Inc.; Durham, NC February 2016 – present

- Engineered software for clients in agricultural and medical research using React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, SQL, and other technologies
- Performed long-term maintenance duties such as bug-fixing, troubleshooting, and server administration

WWOOFer; World Wide Opportunities on Organic Farms; Norway, Germany, and Italy July 2015 – November 2015

Volunteered on organic farms

Full-Stack JEE Developer; Red Hat, Inc.; Richmond, VA

August 2013 – June 2015

- Worked in teams and individually to develop enterprise software solutions using JBoss and other JEE/Java technologies
- Managed client relations

Software Developer Intern; Noblis, Inc.; Center of Applied High Performance Computing, Danville, VA June 2012 – January 2013

 Worked as part of a development team to build a web application for the FAA to interface with a Cray XMT2 supercomputer

Manager; Newcomb Hall, University of Virginia; Charlottesville, VA September 2011 – December 2012

- Managed personnel, set up for school events, and helped customers at the student information desk
- Wrote a software program for my employer to automate employee scheduling

Strong Technologies

Javascript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Mocha/Chai/Jest, C#, Ruby on Rails, Java, Unix Server Administration, SQL (Postgres, MySQL, Oracle), HTML, CSS, Git

Education

University of Virginia, College of Arts and Sciences, Charlottesville, VA August 2009 – May 2013
Graduated with BA - double-major in Computer Science and Philosophy